<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>GGiannis</title><description></description><link>https://ggiannis.com</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 9 Mar 2025 21:50:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Sun, 9 Mar 2025 21:50:20 +0000</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="https://ggiannis.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ggiannis.com/blog/refactoring-vs-rewrite</guid><title>"Refactoring" a word that Management fears</title><description>Discover the key differences between refactoring and rewriting in software development. Learn when to use each approach for optimal project outcomes and code maintenance.</description><link>https://ggiannis.com/blog/refactoring-vs-rewrite</link><pubDate>Sat, 1 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>"Refactoring" a word that Management fears</h2><p>Many developers often confuse refactoring and rewriting as the same thing, but they serve different purposes in software development. Even worse, they might tell Management that a "refactoring" must be done, but in reality, it's a major rewrite! 💥</p><p>Let's break down the differences between the two.</p><h2>What is Refactoring?</h2><p>Refactoring is about cleaning up and improving existing code without changing its functionality. It's like giving your code a makeover—making it easier to read, maintain, and perform better. The goal of refactoring is to enhance the internal structure of the code without altering its external behavior. This process can include renaming variables, reorganizing functions, and improving code structure to make it more efficient and understandable.</p><blockquote><p>💡 In other words, your tests must pass <strong>without any change</strong>.</p></blockquote><h2>What is Rewriting?</h2><p>Rewriting, on the other hand, means starting fresh and building the code from scratch. This approach is often taken to address major architectural issues or to adopt new technologies. Rewriting can lead to a complete overhaul of the codebase, which may involve significant changes in the way the code is structured and implemented. While refactoring is all about incremental improvements, rewriting is a more radical approach that can be time-consuming and resource-intensive.</p><blockquote><p>🫣 Management's nightmare!</p></blockquote><h2>Key Differences</h2><ul><li><strong>Purpose</strong>: Refactoring aims to improve the internal structure of existing code, while rewriting involves creating a new version of the code from scratch.</li><li><strong>Scope</strong>: Refactoring is typically smaller in scope and more incremental, whereas rewriting can be a major overhaul of the entire codebase.</li><li><strong>Outcome</strong>: Refactoring preserves the functionality of the code, while rewriting may result in significant changes in behavior and features.</li></ul><h2>Why Understanding the Difference Matters</h2><p>Knowing the difference between refactoring and rewriting is crucial for effective software development. It helps developers make informed decisions about when to use each approach and ensures that the codebase remains maintainable and efficient over time.</p><p>By understanding these concepts, developers can choose the right strategy for their projects, leading to better outcomes and more sustainable codebases.</p><p>So, the next time you hear the word "refactoring", you'll know exactly what it means and how it differs from rewriting. Happy coding! 👨🏻‍💻</p><blockquote><p>💌 PS: Please correct your collegues, when they often say "this has to be refactored". 😅</p></blockquote>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ggiannis.com/blog/how-to-connect-obsidian-with-nas</guid><title>How to Sync Obsidian iOS with NAS: A Step-by-Step Guide</title><description>Learn how to seamlessly sync your Obsidian iOS app with your NAS and any other remote location.</description><link>https://ggiannis.com/blog/how-to-connect-obsidian-with-nas</link><pubDate>Wed, 8 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Introduction</h2><p>Obsidian is a powerful tool for organizing notes and supports the Zettelkasten method. By default, the iOS app supports iCloud sync functionality. But what if you want to sync your local vault with your <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Network-attached_storage">NAS</a>? The Obsidian iOS app doesn't offer this option, but it's possible to set it up with a bit of effort.</p><h2>Requirements</h2><p>You will need the following:</p><ul><li>Obsidian iOS App</li><li>FileBrowser Pro App (paid). I will refer to it as FBP.</li></ul><h2>Obsidian Setup</h2><p>Start by creating a local vault in the Obsidian app on your iPhone. Ensure that "Store in iCloud" is deselected.</p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/i43snyun7zbt5b94arbac/obsidian-create-vault.jpeg?rlkey=1wmppw8tin482qw7nekrmh6mv&st=4jbj972f&raw=1" class="iphone-screenshot" /><h2>FileBrowser Pro Setup</h2><p>Open the FBP app, tap on "Add Location" choose "App Folder" and select the local vault folder "NAS" from Obsidian's files directory.</p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/c1qqpep4helxkvub1osdf/fbp-map-obsidian-vault.jpeg?rlkey=cuda43vgi0wqlfoqjyik43dlg&st=awoad4se&raw=1" class="iphone-screenshot" /><p>Now that the Obsidian vault is mapped to the FBP app, any content added to the vault will sync with the directory in the FBP app.</p><p>Next, add a remote location in the FBP app. This can be any of the supported options (e.g. Backblaze, Google Drive, OneDrive). I chose "Network Drive".</p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/6buna0lbz5robabltbiw8/fbp-add-remote-location.jpeg?rlkey=aoq1nnlsspr3r0r0qnw9xacla&st=er0td0m0&raw=1" class="iphone-screenshot" /><h2>Sync Setup</h2><p>To sync to and from a remote location, use FBP's custom tasks. Select "Sync Files" from the home screen, then from the bottom left "+" menu, select "Create Custom Task".</p><p>In the Custom Task, add the following steps:</p><ul><li>Tap "Use files from a preset folder..." and select the mapped Obsidian location ("Obsidian NAS" in my case)</li><li>Tap on "Insert Step" to add another step</li><li>Change "Including files/folder" to "Copy to" and select your remote location. (NAS in my case)</li><li>Name the custom task "Sync to NAS"</li></ul><p>Repeat the same steps, reversing the source and destination, and name it "Sync from NAS".</p><p>This setup allows you to:</p><ul><li>Sync the local Obsidian vault to your NAS</li><li>Sync changes from your NAS to the local Obsidian vault</li></ul><p>You can define the sync interval or trigger it manually. I use 1-hour interval to sync to the NAS.</p><h2>Bonus Tip</h2><p>To ensure your local vault is always up to date, create an iOS shortcut that first syncs the vault from the NAS and then opens the Obsidian app.</p><img src="https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/rcacy8tboup2a5b7q99ar/ios-shortcuts-obsidian-sync.jpeg?rlkey=4n1nctvtcok184z550ocd6r8n&st=npagsez5&raw=1" class="content-image" style="width: 60%;" /><p>This setup allows you to sync Obsidian on iOS with various remote locations supported by the FBP app. I hope this guide is helpful. See you in the next post!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ggiannis.com/blog/debug-ios-17-app-via-xcode-14</guid><title>How to Compile and Debug iOS Apps with Different Xcode Versions</title><description>Learn how to compile and debug iOS apps using different Xcode versions. This guide helps you prepare an IPA file and install it on your device, even if your library doesn't support the latest Swift compiler.</description><link>https://ggiannis.com/blog/debug-ios-17-app-via-xcode-14</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Introduction</h2><p>Sometimes it is necessary to compile an app with a specific version of Xcode because a library might not support the latest Swift compiler from Xcode 15. Additionally, you may find that you don't have any iOS 16 devices, which are compatible with Xcode 14. So, what do you do?</p><h2>Solution</h2><p>The solution is not so great but it works. Below you will find the required process.</p><h3>iPA Preparation</h3><ul><li>Navigate to the menu "Product/Archive"</li><li>Start the archive process</li><li>On the presented Organizer window select "Distribute App"</li><li>Select method "Developer"</li><li>Export the archive into a folder of your choice</li></ul><h3>Device Installation</h3><ul><li>Open Xcode 15</li><li>Connect your iOS 17 device</li><li>Open "Window / Devices and Simulators" menu option</li><li>Drag and drop the ipa into your device</li></ul><h3>Debugging</h3><p>Since we don't run the app directly through Xcode we would have to do the following to be able to debug: - Start your app on the phone - Select on Xcode "Debug / Attach to Process"</p><p>If everything goes well you will see that you can hit breakpoints and debug your app as normal.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://ggiannis.com/blog/how-to-connect-sonos-to-pioneer-dj</guid><title>How to connect Sonos Playbase with Pioneer DJ Controller</title><description>Take advantage of connecting the Sonos Playbase to a Pioneer DJ controller to unlock the full potential of both devices.</description><link>https://ggiannis.com/blog/how-to-connect-sonos-to-pioneer-dj</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Introduction</h2><p>All we know that the Sonos devices usually have very few audio output ports. In the case of the Sonos Playbase it's only 1 (Optical). 😅</p><p>In my free time I like DJing and I always wanted to utilize my Sonos speakers, but the Sono's ports were the bottleneck in my setup preventing me to connect my Pioneer DDJ-RR Controller to it.</p><h2>Pioneer DDJ-RR</h2><p>The Pioneer DDJ-RR has the following audio output ports:</p><ul><li>2 x MASTER (XLR, RCA)</li><li>1 x BOOTH (1/4 inch TRS Jack)</li><li>2 x HEADPHONE MONITOR (1/4 inch Jack, mini-jack)</li></ul><p>To keep things simple and the cost as low as possible, I decided to use the MASTER RCA Output to connect it to my Sonos Playbase.</p><h2>Solution</h2><p>To connect the Pioneer DDJ-RR to the Sonos Playbase we will need the following parts:</p><ul><li>1 x Typical RCA cable like <a href="https://www.amazon.de/gp/product/B00FQK327M/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o06_s00?ie=UTF8&psc=1">this</a> one</li><li>1 x AMANKA Analogue to Digital Audio Converter from <a href="https://www.amazon.de/gp/product/B07TXDVVV3/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o05_s00?ie=UTF8&psc=1">Amazon</a>. An alternative from Thomann you can find <a href="https://www.thomann.de/de/swissonic_converter_ad_24_192.htm">here</a>.</li></ul><p>Connect the one end of the RCA cable to the MASTER RCA output of the DDJ-RR and the other end to the Input of the Analogue Digital Converter.</p><p>Set the MASTER RCA as Output in your Pioneer DDJ-RR software, in my case Pioneer DJ Rekordbox. Enjoy mixing having as output your Sonos speakers!</p><blockquote><p>Hint: There is some slight delay (around 35ms) between the monitor output (headphones) and the master output (Sonos Playbase). This is intentionally there from Sonos to allow the surround speakers to sync. Even when there are no surround speakers connected! 😄</p></blockquote><h2>Result</h2><p>You can now use your Sonos System as an output for your DJ Sets and pre-CUE using your headphones. To make the experience even better, group more speakers with the main speaker (Sonos Playbase in my case) in the Sonos App and this way everyone in the apartment can enjoy your mix!</p><h2>Bonus</h2><p>To avoid disconnecting / connecting the optical cable from the Sonos Playbase, you can buy an optical splitter.</p><p>I bought mine from <a href="https://www.amazon.de/gp/product/B00PXSIFWY/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o05_s00?ie=UTF8&psc=10">Amazon</a>. This way you can have both your TV and your DJ Controller permanently connected and switch the output via a remote control.</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>